Isabela Monteiro

Ph: +1 (587) 434 2087 Email:isabelaluizi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/isabelaluizimonteiro

SUMMARY

Self motivated, responsible and adaptable professional currently pursuing Diploma in Web Development (expected graduation May 2020). Strong knowledge in HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, SQL and Laravel. 5+ years of experience in the Oil and Gas industry, hands-on knowledge of terminology and processes with BSC in Chemical Engineering. Good communication and teamwork skills; advanced in English, Spanish and native in Portuguese.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

PHP

JavaScript

SQL

Vue.js

WordPress

Git/Github

CSS

Laravel

SCSS

• C++

Autocad

Maple

 MS Office -Excel, Word, PowerPoint

EDUCATION

Diploma Web Development InnoTech College, Calgary AB

Expected graduation May 2020

Bachelor in Chemical Engineering PUC-RIO, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

International Exchange Program Universidad de Cadiz, Cadiz, Spain

Oct 2019 – present

2008 – 2014

2012 - 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE April 2019 – present

Formula Canada Immigration, Calgary, AB

- Translated documents from English and Spanish to Portuguese
- Participated in consultation sessions as interpreter
- Promoted and solicited orders for the sale of the Company's products and services

Provided administrative support related to clients referred for immigration services

COMMERCIAL ANALYST

Aug 2014 – Dec 2018

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janerio, Brazil

- Developed projects aimed at future gas sales strategies in collaboration with asset and economic teams
- Identified error in invoice by comparing numbers in the sales agreement contracts; resulted in savings of ~\$2M US for the company.
- Presented Natural Gas studies to Repsol Board of Directors (local and international).
- Negotiated gas sales with existing and new clients
- Analyzed gas prices and developed a comprehensive study of potential profits and expenses for potential customers
- Completed supply, demand, infrastructure, and price Natural Gas Market Studies
- Prepared quarterly price forecasts for Natural Gas, LNG and NGL
- Analyzed and tracked regulatory changes in the Brazilian gas market
- Managed the income and expense budget for the department; reported financial data

GAS COMMERCIALIZATION INTERN

Sept 2013 – July 2014

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Trained as gas commercial analyst

LAB ASSISTANT

Aug 2011 – Jun 2012

PUC-RIO, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

• Assisted university students with programming C++ in-class assignments

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Student Mentor

May 2019 – July 2019

Bow Valley College, Calgary, AB

Assisted college students with in-class typing assignments